Luke Cassady-Dorion

Luke@SPStories.com www.luke.gallery

profile

For the past 26 years, I've worked at the intersection of technology and art. I began my career writing Java in the 90s and 00s. During the Web2 era, I launched a YouTube channel that grew to 650K subscribers and received awards for its dedication to social causes. My professional journey includes roles in developer relations, software engineering, video editing, and film directing. I've written books in both English and Thai. I'm at home on camera and excel at helping others feel comfortable in front of an audience.

I'm fluent in English and Thai and speak Spanish at a B1 level. I also have over two decades of experience teaching yoga and Pilates.

experience

Irvs, Developer Relations, 2022 - Present

- Wrote <u>comprehensive documentation</u> detailing the use of our tools and protocol.
- Wrote guides and tutorials that educate developers through project-based learning.
- Created code repositories showcasing clear use cases for our products.
- Developed an <u>open-source UI library</u> to help developers kickstart their projects.
- Designed a gamified developer education experience, leading to over 50K <u>developers completing challenges and minting NFTs</u> as proof of their accomplishments.
- Established and grew our YouTube channel to 33K subscribers.
- Produced <u>educational video content</u>, including animated explainer videos.
- Collaborated with business development and marketing teams to enhance developer outreach.
- Worked 1:1 to support our developers.

A Single Production Company, Co-Founder, 2010 – 2020

 Directed the award-winning feature-length documentary film "<u>The Cheer</u> <u>Ambassadors</u>".

- Directed "<u>D-Dance Dreams</u>", a five-episode TV docuseries telling the story of a group of backup dancers preparing for a large pop concert.
- Directed "<u>Yoga Namaste</u>", a 26-episode TV docuseries telling stories of people whose lives changed as they practiced yoga.
- Launched <u>Picnicly</u>, a YouTube channel dedicated to telling upbeat and inspirational stories, and grew to over 650,000 subscribers.
- Managed a full-time staff of 5 and teams of 20+ contractors on shoots.

AbsoluteYou, Senior Yoga and Pilates Instructor, 2004 – 2023

- Helped grow a boutique fitness studio from 3 to 10 studios and grew our teaching staff from 10 to 100.
- Created written and video content to help train a geographically diverse staff
- Launched a new social media team that led to 200% growth in Instagram and Facebook subscribers.
- Mentored new teachers and worked with them one-on-one to develop skills.

Medem, Co-Founder, CTO, 1999 - 2003

- Raised the quality of online healthcare information by building a one-click tool that physicians used to share peer-reviewed content with their patients.
- Built a HIPAA-compliant secure messaging system connecting physicians and patients.
- Managed a team of 10+ developers.

Metis LLC / Healtheon / WebMD, Senior Software Engineer, 1997 – 1998

- Designed and built a data integration system to merge backend data reporting systems.
- Created a cross-platform Java client that displayed and analyzed data from multiple sources.

publications

- Goto Grok
 Blog on creative coding and Web3 dev
- Yogi Boy: How I Learned To Breathe 2011
 Author (Thai language book)

- Java Distributed Objects 1998
 Co-author and primary editor
- Industrial Strength Java 1997
 Co-author and primary editor
- JavaScript By Example 1996
 Co-author

education

Ramkhamhaeng University, BA Thai Language Studies, 2007-2012

As a personal passion project, I returned to university to study Thai literature and language origins. After 4.5 years, I became the only Westerner to ever graduate from the university's strenuous program.

Drexel University, Computer Science, 1995-1997

After two years, I dropped out to move to San Francisco and help start a healthcare technology company.